

NGO GIA BAO BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE

Mail: ng.giabao1907@gmail.com | Mob: 0779.404.045 | DoB: 19/07/1997

SUMMARY

With 5+ years of experience in Business intelligence, Data analysis, and Finance. I have developed deep insights into operational efficiency, financial management, and technological innovation, always aligning with business objectives and enhancing team performance. My goal is to leverage these insights to drive effective operations and promote sustainable growth for the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Mobile World Investment Corporation | Senior Business Intelligence

2022 - Present

Data Measuring & Planning 50%

- Analyze demand forecasts, product/material performance, warehousing, production, and delivery (e.g., top sales SKUs, active sales, profitability, inventory, loss sales rate)
- Developed processing to update business status across supply chain categories, including prelaunch, launch, and end-of-life
- Providing reports & recommendations changes to reduce or increase of time schedule, goods, and costs
- Extract and manipulate data, build trackers and frameworks to monitor progress and ensure timely completion
- Perform A/B testing and hypothesis testing to validate strategies and drive informed decisions

Adhoc programming & maintenance 30%

- · Well-managed life cycle of product, monitoring start to end processing of productivity
- Crawling data to provide insightful according to actual data and consumer needs, defining key points to develop backup plan
- Build BI dashboards to track key performance indicators, provide actionable insights, and measure business impact

Crisis management & Problem solving: 20%

- Design and propose data-driven solutions to enhance operational efficiency while aligning with strategic objectives
- Collaborate with skateholder and developers for data integration to identify efficiency issues, develop solutions, and implement changes.

Fair Consulting VietNam Co., JSC | Accounting & Tax Consulting |

2019 - 2022

External Accountant Consulting

- Prepare a financial statement monthly and quarterly
- Accounting and tax advisory
- Prepare declaration VAT, PIT, CIT, FCT
- Work with tax authorities and handle tax-related procedures

ACHIEVEMENTS

MWG Corporation | Best Employee of the year 2024 in the Business Analyst Department | Certification Click Here

Increased category revenue of snack shell by 5-10% through optimized product placement in 2 quarters

MWG Corporation | Employee-Innovated Contribution in Operation Management in 2024 | Certification Click Here

 Recognized as Outstanding Operations Employee (2023, 2024) for process optimization & efficiency improvements

SKILL SETS

- **Data analytics:** Proficient in Data collection, processing, analysis, modeling, visualization, reporting and sharing results, storytelling with data, database management systems, knowledgeable in machine learning.
- Technical Skills: Python, MySQL, Power BI, Power Query, Advance in Microsoft Office Tool
- **Soft Skills**: Adaptive, collaborative, effective communication, presentation, teamwork and leadership, project management, Logical & critical thinking, problem-solving, work under high pressure ability.
- Industry Knowledge: Retail, FMCG, Finance.

EDUCATION

Van Lang University

Bachelor of Accounting & Auditing
 2015 - 2019

IIG Viet Nam – HCMC Branch

Certificate of Microsoft Office 365 (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
 2018

MCI Consulting and Analytics Institute

Certificate of Analyzing, Querying and Visualizing Data on Python, SQL, Power BI

REFERENCES

BACH HOA XANH TRADING JOINT STOCK COMPANY

Name: Mr. Nguyen Trung KienPosition: Head of department

• Email: nguyen.trungkien@thegioididong.com

• Mobile: Provide if needed

CAREER ORIENTATION

To become a dedicated employee and work long-term at a company with a high professional standard, in order to facilitate personal growth in terms of professional expertise and mindset, as well as contribute to the company benefits, while accompanying and mutually developing together